what's going on everyone my name is
kotor more and welcome to the third
episode in the new beginner java game
programming tutorial series in this
tutorial we're going to work a little
bit more with our display so before we
get started I am going to make videos
much more often and they're going to be
of much higher quality in just a few
days so by tutorial 6 everything should
be much better I'll have a new computer
so hopefully I'll be able to get things
out much faster and make them properly
because right now my computer can barely
handle recording anyways to today's
tutorial today's tutorial we have a
window so if you run the test code that
we had in the last tutorial we got our J
frame displayed to the screen it's got a
title everything works perfectly but
there's one big problem
there's no graphics in it and if we want
to have a game we need some way to
display graphics to display images to
the screen so today we're going to add
something to this J frame that will
allow us to see images that way we can
eventually have a game that has graphics
so how do we get images into a J frame
well we use something called a canvas so
create a private canvas element called
canvas and when you import it make sure
you import java.awt KS there we go now a
canvas basically allows us to draw
graphics to it so we're going to draw
all of our images such as our player
image our title images all of that we're
going to draw all those images to this
canvas element right here then we're
going to add this canvas element to our
jframe that way we're able to see it I
hope that makes sense and I'm going to
give you guys a quick analogy to
hopefully make some of you understand
this a little bit better if this doesn't
help you that's fine so in real life a
painter will paint his images as
painting on a canvas well in Java we're
going to do the same thing we're going
to paint all of art or draw all of our
images to this canvas object then in
real life when a painter is finished a
painting he will put it in a frame and
display it to the world for the world to
see well in Java we'll do the same thing
we'll draw all of our graphics to the
canvas element then we'll add it to the
jframe that way we're able to see it on
the screen hopefully that makes sense
now so we draw images to the canvas and
then we display the canvas using the
jframe
so let's go ahead and initialize that
canvas equals a new canvas and we also
have to set the size
our canvas so canvas set preferred size
and canvas doesn't just take in a width
and height as parameters it takes in a
new dimension object and that takes in a
width in height and that's just the way
canvases were created so that will set
the preferred size of our canvas the
size that we want our canvas to be which
is the width in height of our game we're
going to copy this line down two more
times and instead of set preferred size
we're going to do set maximum size and
we're going to do set minimum size this
is to make sure that our canvas will
always stay at the width and height that
we give it so we set the size we want it
to be a two width and height then we set
the maximum and minimum size of it to
width and height this will make sure it
stays at the width and height that we
give it so we initialize our canvas we
set the size of it now we have to
actually add it to our Dre frame frame
add canvas it's as simple as that
then at the end we have to do framed up
PAC and framed up PAC will basically
resize our window a little bit that way
we're able to see the canvas fully if
you don't have framed up PAC everything
will still work but you might not see
all of the canvas so there we go
we have just added a canvas with the
size that we give it to our J frame to
our window so if you run the test code
that we created in the last tutorial
we'll get our window displayed to the
screen everything's the same and that's
a problem everything is the same
well we added our canvas but there's
nothing within our window and that's
because we haven't actually drawn
anything to the canvas yet we haven't
told the canvas to draw anything to our
J frame sadly we can't draw anything
just yet because we have much more
preparation before we can do that but I
just wanted to get that done in this
tutorial next we're going to have to
create a new class right click on your
main package and go up to new class we
are going to name this class game and
we'll put it in our main package there
we go now the game class is going to be
the main class the main part of our game
it will hold all of the base code for
our game it'll start everything it'll
run everything and it'll close our game
so this game is very important it's
going to be the main class of our game
we're going to put a lot of stuff in
this class so let's go ahead and create
the game constructor here
and our game is going to need an
instance of our display class here so
we'll create a private display object
called display and then we have to
initialize our display in our game
constructor display equals new display
now our display class takes in a title a
width and a height so we'll take those
in as parameters in our game constructor
as well width and height and we'll just
pass those right along to our display
there we go so now whenever we create a
new game instance a new game class
instance it'll automatically set a
display for itself to have now I'm also
going to create a few public integers at
the top here width and height and I am
just going to set those to the two
parameters that we passed in here that
way this class also has access to the
women hi easily so this dog would that
goes width and the Sahai equals height
so now whenever we create a new game
like that it should set the width and
height variables up here then initialize
a new display and hopefully get a
display to the screen so if you go into
your launcher class instead of having a
new display we'll create a new game
instance and we'll pass in our game
title mine will be tile game and then
the width and height that you want it
I'll make mine 400 by 400 there we go
that should do it
go ahead and run your new launcher class
that'll create a new game object and
look we still have a window displayed to
the screen it's a size that I gave it it
has a title that I gave it everything
works the same it'll have the canvas in
it the only thing that's different is
that we're running it from our game
class in the next tutorial we're going
to add much more to this game class and
hopefully get graphics to the screen in
the next couple of tutorials thanks for
watching everyone I'll see you in the
next one